These players who think it's
all about their agility,
man, they're living in a dream.
I mean, sure,
firing speed and evasion are important,
and time was, if you rock those two
things, it's all you needed to be the best.
Till now, that is.
Yeah, hate to say it, but it
don't work like that anymore.
In fact,
I got a message for
the folks who spent the
last eight months indoors
boosting their AGI.
Sucks to be you right now, Tony.
Now that's the kind of comment we'd expect
from the top player of Gun Game Online,
one of the most challenging VR Miss.
Talk about controversial.
I guess, but who knows if
I'll be on MMO stream again,
so might as well stir things up.
Oh, please.
So, do you think you have a shot
in the upcoming bullet of bullets?
Damn right, honey.
I wouldn't be in it if I
didn't think I could win it.
It won't be that easy to succeed.
The B .O .B.'s a solo journey,
so it's way different.
What worked for you up to now
doesn't mean it'll work again.
If I were you, I wouldn't chalk
my wins up to my status type.
Yeah, well, if anything, my results point
to some big changes happening in G .G .O.
You're all about A .G .I., Yamikaze.
Go figure you'd be in denial.
Wake up, people! Till now,
the best strategy was
boosting your AGI and
shooting a powerful gun
as fast as you could.
But the reality is, the balance of
gameplay in an MMO is always changing.
Especially in games like this one,
with levels that don't let
you respect your stats.
You have to think ahead and be
smart when using your points,
because the best weapon in one level
zone might not work for you in the next.
Besides,
the new guns coming out
are gonna have higher
strength requirements
and accuracy bonuses.
You remember when he was talking
about how great being an AGI type was?
That dick totally scammed us.
You're nothing but a fake sex seed.
And now, you'll face judgement
from someone with real power.
All I'm saying is, what's really important
in the end is the player's ability to...
Uh-oh, I guess we have
a bad connection here.
Don't worry, folks, I'm
sure he'll be back shortly.
Stay tuned for more MMO's dream.
This is real power, real strength.
Let your fear carve one
name into your brains.
The name I share with
this weapon, Death Gun.
December 7th, 2025.
Has it already been a year?
I wonder what the difference is
between the real world and the virtual.
The amount of data, that's all.
You scared me.
Sorry about that.
I'm on time, though.
What?
No, I'm sorry.
I was spacing out.
Anyway, hello, Kirito.
How are you doing today?
It's been good so far,
but it's even better now.
What are you staring at? Nothing.
Just, uh, that outfit looks good on you.
It brings back a lot of memories.
I guess it does.
No rapier, though.
Looks like you went
overboard on the black today.
Yeah.
Sugu threw everything in
the wash this morning.
And this is all I had left.
Then stop putting your laundry off.
I can't believe we both dressed
in our old colors today.
What are the odds of that?
Well, if we see each other
every day for a year, it's...
That was a rhetorical
question, Smarty Pants.
Come on.
Okay, okay.
I don't know about you, but I think
the Imperial Palace is interesting.
Interesting?
What do you mean?
It's two kilometers north to south,
1.5 east to west, and it
takes up 20 % of Chiyoda Ward.
There aren't any subways or tunnels
under it, and it's a no-fly zone.
It's kind of cool, don't you think?
I mean, it's this big restricted
area right in the middle of Tokyo.
Not only is it cut off from everything
physically, but information-wise as well.
See that?
It's a surveillance camera.
This place was set up with
its very own closed network.
You can't even access it from the outside.
Wow, that's a weird-looking camera.
Yeah.
Not only is this place the heart of Tokyo,
but it's also an isolated
world of its own.
Maybe I'm exaggerating its cool factor.
I get like that. You think?
Wow.
This used to be the inner citadel.
Come on, let's go!
Hey, you know that questionnaire
they gave us to fill out?
The one about our future plans?
Do you know what you want to do yet?
Hmm.
I guess, if anything, I want to go from
playing games to being a creator. A creator?
What, for games?
No, not for games.
I want to make a human-machine interface
to replace the full-dive tech we use now.
I've been going to all these tech
forums to learn more about it,
but it's a heck of a lot
of information to absorb.
After I graduate, all I
want is to be with you. Huh?
I mean, I wish we could figure out a
way to live with Yui in this world, too.
We'll be able to live with her someday,
as soon as we figure out how to
access augmented reality at will.
The only thing standing in the way is
the difference in the amount of data.
Didn't you say something
like that a little while ago?
That the difference between our world
and the virtual was the amount of data?
What does that mean, anyway?
Let's see.
It's like this.
If we were holding hands in AOLO,
it wouldn't be the same as
in the real world, would it?
No, it wouldn't.
You can feel a lot more
touching a real hand.
Hey, is that what you mean by the
difference in the amount of data?
Yep.
And can you imagine
what it would be like if
we could reproduce the
feel of skin in a pulse?
Would we be able to tell the difference
between a real hand and an avatar's hand?
I know I could, if I
was touching your hand.
But it's not just touch, is it?
I mean, in the real world,
we get a lot of information from
how something sounds or tastes.
Even if our atmosphere rigs
could access augmented reality,
we'd still know the difference.
Yeah, the second you saw or touched
something, you'd know if it was real or not.
But hopefully, someone will come along
and make a technological breakthrough.
And whatever that is, it'll have to
output a ton of sensory data all the time.
Then we could break down the wall between
both worlds and be with Yui forever.
Do you think that day
will ever come for us?
Yeah.
Then get to work and make
it happen, okay? Okay?
Welcome, sir.
Hey, Kirito!
Over here!
Go ahead.
Order whatever you want. It's on me.
Thank you, sir.
That's very kind of you. Come on.
You don't have to be so formal with me.
Relax and talk to me
like you would in ALO.
Okay.
If you say so, then I guess I'll...
I'd like the parfait au chocolate, the
framboise milfouille, and a hazelnut latte.
Sorry to make you come all
the way out here, Kirito.
If you're that sorry about it,
why'd you ask me to come to Ginza?
Oh, and do you think you cannot
call me by that name in public?
What's with all the attitude?
I thought we were buds.
I was the first to visit you
in the hospital, remember?
He's right.
When I came to, the first
one there wasn't my family.
It was the leader of the task force.
Seijiro Kikuoka,
from the Tech Bureau at the Ministry
of Internal Affairs and Communications,
a .k .a.
the Virtual Reality Section.
So what'd you want to see me about?
If it's anything SAO-related,
I told you everything I know.
Actually, I want to talk to
you about something else.
Have a look at that.
Who's he?
This won't be pleasant.
So last month, on November the 14th,
the landlord of an
apartment complex in Nakano,
Tokyo, noticed a foul odor while cleaning.
It was coming from one of the units.
So he disabled the lock and
discovered this man, dead.
His name was Tamotsu
Shigemura when he was 26.
He'd been dead for five days.
They found him in bed.
His place was a mess,
but no signs of burglary.
He had something interesting
on his head, though.
An amrusphere? Yeah.
It was ruled an unnatural
death, so they did an autopsy.
The cause of death was found
to be acute heart failure.
Wait, heart failure?
You mean his heart stopped?
They find out why?
No, they didn't.
Here you are, sir.
Unfortunately,
since so much time had
passed since his death
and foul play was ruled out as the cause,
the autopsy wasn't very thorough.
We do know he'd been
logged in for two days
straight and hadn't eaten
anything the whole time.
Well, that's not that unusual.
Players do it all the time.
Wait, why are you telling me about this?
He had a game installed on his
system called Gun Gale Online.
You know that one?
Yeah, GGO.
It's the only MMO in Japan
with professional players.
This past October, there was a tournament
to decide the most powerful player in GGO.
The deceased was the guy who won it.
His character's name was Zekseed.
Was he playing GGO when he died? No.
When it happened, he was appearing on a
show called MMO Stream as Zekseed's avatar.
We know the time from the logs.
This next bit of info still
needs to be confirmed.
According to another player's blog,
at the same time Shigemura had the heart
attack, something strange happened in GGO.
What?
Some players were at a bar
in-game watching the show when
one of the players stood up
and started acting erratically.
The blog states,
The player was shouting stuff
about judgment and power
at Zexeed's image on the TV
and then fired his gun at it.
At the time, another player in the
bar happened to be recording audio.
He uploaded it to a video site.
Since the file had a Japan
Standard Time counter embedded.
We know that the shot fired at the TV and
Shigemura's avatar
disappearing from the show?
happened at about the same time.
Probably just coincidence.
There was another death, though. What?
This one happened on November the
28th, somewhere in Saitama Prefecture.
Same setup as before.
The deceased was found in their apartment.
A guy delivering the newspaper
happened to look in the window.
He saw the victim lying in
bed wearing an AmuSphere rig.
Said the smell was...
Let's skip the details of
the corpse's condition.
Anyway, heart failure
was the cause of death.
The victim was also a
top-ranking GGO player.
His character's name was Usushio Tarako?
Well, he was playing when he died.
It happened in the
central plaza in Glocken.
He was in the middle of
a meeting with his squad.
I guess that's the same as a guild.
A strange player went up to
him and shot him, point-blank.
Do you know if it was the
same guy who shot Zekseed?
Most likely.
He said stuff about judgment and power,
and then identified himself
with the same character name.
What name?
Death Gun.
Death Gun?
Are you absolutely sure both
victims died from heart failure?
What do you mean?
Was there any damage to their brains?
I was wondering about that, too.
So I asked the coroner if he found any
trace of damage to either of their brains,
and he said they were both fine.
Besides, the NerveGear rig
used high-output microwaves,
powerful enough to fry the signal
elements and destroy the brain.
On the other hand,
the Amusphere rig was designed so that it
couldn't emit electromagnetic
waves that powerful.
At least, that's what
the developers claim.
It sounds like you guys
have done your homework,
but even so, your story's built
around coincidence and rumors. True.
It could be a coincidence or even a hoax.
I'm not sold either way.
For now, and this is
hypothetical, mind you.
Do you think it's even remotely
possible to stop a player's
heart in the real world with
virtual bullets from a virtual gun?
No, I don't think so.
But hypothetically,
let's say this death gun
did send some kind of killer
signal to Zekseed and that
Tarako guy's ammospheres.
What would it be?
Could the sensation of
a touch stop a heart?
Maybe a taste or smell?
A sight, a sound?
Or some other sensation?
Okay, whoa.
You already thought of this, haven't you?
Oh, I get it.
You and your team can't figure it out, so
you invite me for coffee to pick my brain?
No, what are you talking about?
I'd never do something
like that to you, honest.
I liked talking to you and
just wanted your opinion.
We're done.
You want my opinion?
Here it is.
You can't stop a player's heart in
the real world by actions in-game.
Shots fired and the heart
attacks are coincidences.
Wait, hold on.
Listen, you can order something else.
Just sit down and hang out for a bit.
Please.
I can't tell you how relieved I
am to hear you put it into words.
Fact is, I'm of the same opinion as you.
I don't believe these two deaths were
caused by in-game gunshots either.
And now that we've talked, I
want to ask you officially.
Would you log into Gun
Gale Online and make
contact with the player
calling himself Death Gun?
And once I do find the guy, then what?
You want me to get shot, is that it?
Whoa now, come on.
Well, screw that.
I don't want to get killed.
That's not possible.
We just agreed it wasn't, didn't we?
Besides, this Death Gun guy is
only going after specific targets.
They have to meet his criteria.
Criteria? Uh-huh.
Here's the deal.
Zekseed and Usushio Tarako
weren't just any old players.
They were top-ranked, so it's safe to
assume he's not interested in newbies.
But if you were strong enough to
beat Kayaba at his own game, then...
That's different!
Look, I don't know what you've
heard, but GGO's no walk in the park.
It's filled with pro gamers!
Hold the phone!
You said pro gamer.
What does that mean, pro?
It means professional. Literally.
Gungale Online is the only
virtual MMO with a game
Control currency
conversion system in place.
What?
It means whatever money you earn in
the game gets paid back to you in cold,
hard cash in the real world.
Being a pro means you
have a constant stream
of income from the game
coming in every month.
And if you're a top player, that means
monthly you're making $200,000 to $300,000.
It's an awesome gig.
That's why the high-level
guys in GGO are so hardcore.
They pour more time and passion into
it than players from other Miss.
Someone like me can't just log
in and match players like that.
You should find someone else.
Whoa, hold it, hold it.
Who else am I going to find?
You're it.
I need your help in this investigation.
and if taking these pros on is going to be
that big a deal, I can pay you this much.
I don't get why you're so hung up on this.
You find horror stories like
these all the time online.
Yeah, I know.
But still, it's got my bosses worried.
The effect of full-dive technology on the
real world is the hottest topic today.
Literally everyone's researching it.
People are going to try to use these
deaths to regulate the technology.
We want to know the facts
before that happens.
We want to be sure.
That's why we're interested.
You guys could just go directly
to the admins about it. Right.
But Zaskar, the company that developed
and hosts GGO, is in the U .S.
Their address, phone number, and email?
None of it's been made public,
so we can't contact them.
Ever since the seed was released, all kinds
of shady VR worlds have popped up. Yeah.
Maybe they're legit, maybe they're not.
But if we want to find anything out,
the only way to do it is to try
contacting them in the game.
I'm not asking you to get shot.
We'll take whatever safety
precautions we have to.
Just evaluate the
situation and report back.
So will you help us or what?
4,000 people died in Aincrad.
It's been a year and finally those
memories are starting to fade.
But now, more people are dying
in another virtual world,
and I'm getting pulled back in.
It's like someone doesn't
want me to ever forget.
Oh, now I get it.
I think I figured out why
you brought me here today.
Oh, you did, huh? Mm-hmm.
If our world is made up of an axis
called time and a plane called space,
then the center of our reality is
this place, in the heart of Tokyo,
where a castle used to stand.
And the axis of all the
virtual worlds popping up now,
thanks to the Seed, is a place that
also had a castle once, Aincrad.
That's why this sunset
feels so nostalgic now.
You're right.
It does.
You know, what you just said helped
me figure something out, too.
Huh? Really?
You remember what Aincrad
looked like? Well,
maybe its shape was supposed to represent
the axis of time and the plane of space.
Maybe.
But if its vertical axis represented
time and its floor is space,
then the Commander made a
world that tapered to nothing.
Everything ended once you reached the top.
Unfortunately, a certain
someone destroyed it halfway up.
Now we'll never know how it ended.
Yes, ma 'am.
Sorry about that, ma 'am.
Asuna, listen, I... What?
Nah.
Hey, it's getting cold.
You want to start heading back now?
Mm-hmm.
Oh, and next time we come, let's
bring Liz and Leafa and the others.
Wouldn't it be fun to get everyone
together for a picnic here?
Yeah, it would.
Especially in springtime.
I'm in position. Roger.
Targets haven't changed
their course or their speed.
They're 400 meters from you, 1500 from me.
Pretty far.
Can you make the shot?
No sweat. Okay, then. Fire when ready.
I'm counting on you, Sinon.
Roger.
this pressure this anxiety this fear
1500 meters that's nothing like tossing a
lot of paper into a trash can no way
this is nothing like how it felt that day
Next
Let's go.
I'll
see
you
next time.